A NETFLIX ORIGINAL SERIES
What's this? A blindfold?
（永井圭(ながいけい)）
こ… これは！
目隠し？
Hatred of humans...
（佐藤(さとう)）
人間への憎悪
We gave him over to the humans
so he could learn it first-hand.
その全てを植え付けるために
彼を人間側に差し出したんだ
How could they? Why is this...
（圭）
ひどい…
どうして僕が…
Do you finally get it?
（田中功次(たなかこうじ)）
やっと分かったか？
When it comes down to it,
you still want them to help you.
いざとなったら助けを求める
最低なクズ
That's right... Kill...!
そうだ… 殺せ！
本当の自分になれ！
Embrace your true nature!
There's an intruder!
The man in the hat has gotten inside!
（警備員）
侵入者です！
帽子の男が侵入してきました！
Did he come to rescue Nagai
after leaving him behind?
（戸崎優(とさきゆう)）
永井を助けに来た？
見捨てておいて？
Man, why all the commotion?
（オグラ･イクヤ）
ったく… なんで
こんなに騒がしいんだ？
Even though the great
Ikuya Ogura is here.
このオグラ･イクヤ様が
来たってのに
Well then, Nagai...
さて 永井君 お迎えだよ
I've come to get you.
（泣き声）
（圭）
佐藤さん…
Mr. Sato.
I'm so sorry
to have caused you such trouble.
お手数おかけして すみません
Well, this was...
（佐藤）
この仕上がりは失敗だな…
...a failure.
Well then, let's go.
We can't stay here too long.
さあ 行こうか　長居は禁物だよ
あ… はい
Right.
AJIN: DEMI-HUMAN
深く眠れるかい？
傷は癒せたかい？
Do you sleep well?
Did your wounds heal?
Just cos' they say the night is lonely
夜が寂しいからって
You don't have to force yourself
To love someone
無理して
誰かを愛さないで
夢を見る事だって
咽び泣く事だって
They say I'm dreaming
They say I'm sobbing
知りもしないまま
死んでみたって
They say I tried to die without knowing
上手に隠れたかい？
息は潜めたかい？
Did you manage to hide?
Did you hold your breath?
Just cos' they say it's tough now
今が苦しいからって
You don't have to force yourself to change
無理して自分変えないで
勇敢な蛮人だって
悩める子羊だって
Even a brave savage
Even a troubled lamb
回り道して生きているって
They are just wandering through life
目立たないように
So I don't stand out
堪えられるように
So I can put up with it
So my train of thought won't stop yet
思考回路はまだ
止めないように
今宵 RUN A WAY  RUN A WAY
Tonight run away, run a way
It's unbelievable
嘘みたいだ
誰かこの手
掴んでくれよ
Someone take my hand
見えない明日は来なくていい
The tomorrow we can't see
Doesn't have to come
今はただ　眠りたい
Now I just want to sleep
I'm gonna kill you too
Does this bother you?
（佐藤）
気になるかい？
え？　あ… 別に
Not really.
It must have been their job
to protect this place,
ここを守るのが
この人たちの仕事でしょうし
and they're dead now anyway.
もう 死んじゃってますしね
ハハ… そうだね
You're right.
（圭）
そんなことより―
More importantly, I absolutely do
want to get out of here,
こんな所 絶対 脱出したいので
よろしくお願いします
so if you'd be so kind...
Then let's hurry.
じゃあ 急ごう
This kid...
（佐藤）
この子…
I remember now that something felt off
when I first met him.
初めて話した時に抱いた違和感を
思い出した
He said he was worried about his sister,
but somehow didn't really sound sincere.
妹の心配を口にはしているが
どこか うそくさい感じ…
亜人という以前に
もっと根本的に この子はおかしい
Apart from being an Ajin,
he was strange to begin with.
I thought he'd turned out a failure...
仕上がりは失敗かと思ったが
もう少し様子を見るか
but I think I'll keep an eye on him
a little longer.
（物音）
（圭）
はっ…
Don't shoot.
（野村(のむら)）
撃つな！
我々は警備員じゃない
We're not guards.
（圭）
ほっ…
Let's hurry on out of...
（圭）先を急ぎま…
（銃声）
（圭）
あっ
（野村）くっ…
（近藤(こんどう)）ひっ…
あの… 殺すんですか？
You're killing them?
Yeah.
うむ… 万全を期す
Just to make sure.
（野村）
くっ…
（佐藤）
くっ… 永井君
Nagai?
あ… いえ あの…
It's just, I mean...
I know you rescued me,
so it's hard to say this,
助けていただいている身分で
大変 言いにくいんですが―
but they're not fighting back,
so maybe you don't need to kill them.
無抵抗ですし
殺さなくてもいいんじゃ…
（佐藤）
麻酔銃を隠してるかも
They could be hiding tranquilizer guns.
Well, then how about just blinding them
or breaking their arms?
あ… じゃあ 目を潰すとか
腕を折るとかは どうです？
Nagai. You really are...
（佐藤）
永井君　君は やはり…
（圭）
あっ…
（佐藤）
失敗だったよ
...a failure.
（銃声）
ぐっ…
Did you just shoot me?
私を… 撃ったな
I-- I'm sorry.
あ… ごめんなさい
つい とっさに…
I did it without thinking.
ごふっ…
Nagai.
永井…
I'm gonna...
君も… ぶち殺してやる
...kill you too.
IBMs are solid matter.
（オグラ）
ＩＢＭは物質だよ
Then why can't we see them?
（コウマ）
じゃあ なぜ見えない？
Can you see this?
（オグラ）
これが見えるか？
（コウマ）
は？
It's lesson time. Light comes from
its source and reflects off solid objects,
（オグラ）
お勉強タイムだ
光源から放たれた光は
物質に反射し―
and when it reaches our eyes,
that's how people see.
それを目が受け取り
人は物を見ている
So, then why is glass transparent?
じゃあ なぜガラスは透明なのか
それは ガラスが
光を透過する性質の物質で―
Because glass is a solid material
that allows light to pass through it.
構成されているからだ
Most glass is 80 to 90 percent
transparent.
一般的なガラスの透過率は
80から90パーセント
IBMs are composed entirely of an unknown
substance that's 100 percent transparent.
ＩＢＭは全身が
透過率100パーセントの―
未知の物質で構成されているんだよ
Don't take him too seriously,
Colonel Kouma.
（岸(きし)）
あまり真に受けるなよ 陸佐
This guy was always coming up
with crazy theories.
（岸）
突拍子もない理論ばかりで
誰からも相手にされなかった男だ
No one ever took him seriously.
日本ではな
In Japan, anyway.
（岸）
雑な国に認められたのが―
Are you really that happy to get credit
in such a crude country, Ikuya?
そんなにうれしいか イクヤ君
It's that stubbornness of yours
そんな石頭だから―
that's keeping you from moving on
to the next stage, Dr. Kishi.
ネクストステージに
行けんのですよ　岸先生
（下村泉(しもむらいずみ)）
出てきませんね
They're not coming out.
備品室はカメラの圏外
これでは様子が…
The equipment room is out of camera range.
We can't tell what's going on.
Mr. Tosaki.
（泉）
戸崎さん あの…
Are you sure I shouldn't be fighting?
私は戦ったりしなくても
いいんですか？
（戸崎）
いいに決まってるだろ
Of course I'm sure.
If they manage to get in here,
who else would protect me?
ここへ攻め込まれでもしたら
誰が私を守るんだ？
You stay here.
君は ここにいろ
絶対に どこへも行くなよ
Don't even think about going
anywhere.
はい
Yes, sir.
Where are you hiding?
（佐藤）
どこに隠れた？
はっ！
I don't have any weapons.
（圭）
武器もない　ルートも分からない
And I don't know the way out.
How can I escape?
どう脱出すればいい？
I never thought I'd be hiding
alongside an Ajin.
（近藤）
まさか
亜人と隠れることになるとはな
（野村）
よせ　かばってくれたんだぞ
-Cut it out. He protected us.
-Don't make me laugh.
ふざけんな！　そもそも
こいつが やつを呼び寄せたんだ
He's the one who brought him here.
How many people are dead because of him?
こいつのせいで
何人 死んだと思ってんだ
I wasn't the one who killed them,
you know?
僕が殺したわけじゃないですよ
And besides, if you're going
to bring that up...
第一 それを言うなら―
I haven't exactly forgotten
what you've done to me either.
あんたらが僕にしたことを
忘れたわけじゃないからな
んん… 必ず解剖台に戻してやる
I swear I will get you back
on the dissection table.
嫌だ！　死んでも戻りたくない
Screw you! There's no way
you're getting me back there.
I'm getting out of here...
one way or the other.
僕は 絶対に ここから脱出する
You guys want
to get out of here too, don't you?
あんたらも外へ避難したいんだろ？
We both want the same thing.
目的は一緒
ギブ･アンド･テークだ
It's time for a little give and take.
I'll be the decoy and get you two out.
僕が おとりになって
あんたらをここから出す
In return, you'll show me the route
to get out of here safely.
あんたらは 僕に
安全に外まで行けるルートを示す
Are you sure about being a decoy?
（野村）
い… いいのか？　おとりなんて…
It's not like I can die.
死なないですし
-That's not true.
-Shut up! He's willing to help us.
（野村）
それは違う…
よせよ！　やる気になってんだから
（圭）
うん？
Nagai, are you listening?
（佐藤）
永井君 聞いてるかな？
（３人）
はっ！
You're probably feeling somewhat secure
in the belief that you can't die.
死なない安心感が あらゆる判断を
安易にさせているんだろう
When I said I'd kill you,
it wasn't just a figure of speech.
私が殺すと言ったのは比喩ではない
Ajins can die.
亜人は死ぬんだ
Damn it, now he's done it.
ちっ 余計なことを…
え？
I suppose it depends
on how you define death, but...
（佐藤）
死をどう定義するかにもよるが…
when Ajins die, they regenerate
亜人は 大きな肉片を核に
散らばった肉片を集めて再生する
by gathering the smaller pieces
to the largest piece.
But if the pieces are too far away,
they're just remade.
だが 遠くに行きすぎた肉片は
回収されず 新しく作られる
What if that piece is your head?
もし それが頭だったら？
フッ 約束しよう
I promise you.
I am going to cut off your head.
私は今から 必ず君を断頭する
Then I'll pick up that head...
そして その頭を拾い上げ―
and I will force it to watch a new one
being regenerated until it dies.
新しい頭が作られてしまうさまを
絶命するまで観察させる
So, then, is this new head,
its brain, its soul...
さて 新しく出来た
頭は 脳は 心は 今の君なのか？
actually you?
No.
否だ
You're over here.
（佐藤）
君は こっち　ここでおしまい
It's all over for you.
はぁっ…
I will make you regret ever killing me.
私を殺したことを
死ぬほど後悔させてやる
ああっ…
Nagai Kei...
（野村）
永井… 圭君
you don't have to help us.
やめても構わないよ
（圭）え…
（近藤）は！？
ああっ…
I will though.
やめない
I'll get you out.
あんたらを外に出す
That's what I should do...
そうするべきだ… 多分
I think.
あ…
（圭）
狙いは首の後ろ… 脊髄(せきずい)
Get the back of his neck, his spinal cord.
うまくいけば
殺さず 全神経を断てる
If I do it right, I can cut off
all his nerves without killing him.
なっ…
（刺さる音）
（圭）うっ…
（佐藤）
ハハハハ…！
うわあっ！
ううっ…
ぐっ… ああーっ！
ううっ！
（銃声）
-What are you doing?!
-We made a promise!
何してんだ？
約束しただろ！
Aiding and abetting his flight.
I'm not taking responsibility!
（近藤）
逃走幇助(ほうじょ)とか 俺は責任取んねぇぞ
痛っ… ぐぅっ…
やめとけば よかった
This was a bad idea.
Damn it, damn it!
くそっ くそっ！
なんで こんな目に！
Why is this happening to me?!
くっ…
What's that?
何だ？　それは…
Why is there so much?
何なんだ？　その量は
（圭）
あ…
ああ…
If that... happens... I'll kill them.
（圭ＩＢＭ）
その時は…
殺してやる
So this is Nagai's.
（佐藤）
これが永井君の… 形状はプレーン
It looks ordinary.
痛っ…
How about just...
（圭ＩＢＭ）
腕を折るとかは… どうです？
breaking their arms?
（佐藤）
ぐわっ！
It's true that the black ghosts
sometimes repeat words
確かに黒い幽霊は―
命令せずとも 言葉を反復したり
少し うろついたりはするが…
or wander around without orders.
うがっ！
（圭ＩＢＭの叫び声）
But this one's... way too independent!
（佐藤）
こいつは ちょっと勝手すぎだよ
I'm so sorry to have caused you
so much trouble.
（圭ＩＢＭ）
お手数をおかけして すみません
Invisible people made
of an unknown substance?
（岸）
未知の物質で出来た透明人間？
And what exactly does that have to do
with Ajins not dying?
それが亜人の不死と
何の関係があるんだね？
Tell me this. Why do people eat oranges?
（オグラ）
人は なぜ ミカンを食べるのか
はぁ？
Serves you right.
ざまあみろ
あれのおかげで助かった
I got away thanks to that thing.
People can't generate vitamin C
on their own.
（オグラ）
人はビタミンＣを
自ら生成することが出来ない
So they have to get it
through other sources such as fruit.
だから 果物などから
摂取する必要がある
The black ghost.
黒い幽霊…
亜人は あれが出せるんだ
So Ajins can summon those.
（オグラ）
栄養失調で死んだ亜人は―
Ajins who die of malnutrition
can even make their own vitamins
再生時 それすら
作り出すことが出来るんだ
when they regenerate.
Wait, what has that got to do
with not dying!?
ていうか 不死身と関係ないだろ
ううっ…
ふぅ…
There's no way that's unrelated
to their ability
未知の物質を作り出すことと
無関係のはずがない
to generate an unknown substance.
（圭）
ああ… はぁっ… いってぇ
はぁっ… はぁっ…
（近藤）
What is it?
（野村）
どうした？
I'm going to hide out in this room.
（近藤）
俺は この部屋でやり過ごす
Did you ever think that the killer
might follow the line to us, too?
目印をたどって あの人殺しまで
ついてくるかも知れねぇだろ
はぁ…
（足音）
はぁ… はぁっ…
All right!
よし！
え！？
ひぃっ…
うっ… うっ な… 何？
What?
（佐藤ＩＢＭ）
あ… 見えるかい？
You can see it?
Sometimes people can see these,
強い感情を向けた時
人間にも これが見えることがある
when there's a strong feeling
directed at them.
Like the urge to kill, for example.
（佐藤ＩＢＭ）
殺意… とかね
（近藤）
はっ… たた… 助けて…
Please don't.
Sorry, that won't work.
（佐藤ＩＢＭ）
すまない　無理だ
To tell the truth, I rather like killing.
私はねぇ
殺すのが結構 好きなんだよ
（近藤）
うっ ううっ うっ…
（悲鳴）
ああっ… はぁっ… はぁっ…
Nagai, over here!
（野村）
永井君 こっちだ！
（圭）
うん？　ああっ はぁっ…
Why are you still here?
なんで まだ いるんですか？
I had to show you how
to use the fire escape chute.
（野村）
火災用脱出シュート
これの使い方を教えないと
（圭）
あ… いやいや
要らないですよ 僕には
I don't need that.
Oh, right.
（野村）
あ そうか
I wonder if this height will kill me.
この高さで死ねるかな？
But that's not the only reason
why I waited.
（野村）
けど それだけで
待ってたわけじゃないんだ
え？
Once we get down,
I can drive you somewhere in my car.
（野村）
下に降りたら 俺の車で
どこかまで送ってもいいよ
は？
I told myself it was just my job,
（野村）
仕事だと割り切っていたが
本当に ひどいことをしたから
but we really did such cruel things
to you.
There's one more thing I wanted
to reassure you about.
あと１つ 安心してほしいことが
That you're still you.
君は 君のままってこと
We never once beheaded you
during the experiments,
実験中
一度も断頭は行ってないし―
and no brain cells were left at the
accident site either.
トラック事故現場にも
脳細胞は残されていなかった
I just wanted you to know that.
それだけ伝えたかったんだ
How is it that you're able
to worry about others?
（圭）
なんで
他人を気遣えるんですか？
（野村）
ん？
Can you actually understand
other people's pain?
人の痛みなんて分かります？
It's just… I've never really worried
about anyone else before.
僕は うわべ以外で
人の心配なんてしたことない
Nagai, you really are quite interesting.
（佐藤）
永井君 君は やはり興味深い
Including that personality
your sister talked about.
妹さんの言ってた人間性も含めてね
What kind of person your brother is.
（荒木(あらき)）
お兄さんが どんな人間か…
That's what those two asked you?
その２人組に
そう聞かれたんだね？
Yeah.
（永井慧理子(ながいえりこ)）
ええ
（荒木）
それで 何て？
And what did you say?
My brother is...
兄さんは…
...a jerk.
（慧理子）
クズ
（銃声）
（圭）わあっ！
（圭）
ああ…
The wind's blowing hard.
風が強いな
（野村）
隠れろ
Hide!
（圭）
うっ ああ…
（野村）
ううっ！ あっ…
Jerk? That's...
（荒木）
クズって…　ハハッ そんな…
クズよ
He is.
（荒木）
ああっ…
Deep down my brother is very logical,
cold, and calculating.
兄さんの本質は
合理的で どこまでも冷たい
That's the kind of person he is.
あの人は―
そういう人間なの
（圭）
あ～あ 死んじゃあ
もう助けようがないな…
Well, I can't help him if he's dead.
So, what's the quickest way out?
最短距離は… あっちだ！
うっ！ いっ…
（空撃ちの音）
Too bad.
うーん 残念　弾切れか
Out of bullets.
（圭）ううっ…
（野村のせきこみ）
へ！？
（野村）
うう…
Wait, he's still alive?!
まだ生きてるのか！？
This is the final stage, Nagai.
最終ステージだ　永井君
（圭）
なっ… ああっ…
Damn it!
くっそー！
ええぃ…
Black ghost!
黒い幽霊！　もう一度 出ろ！
Come out again!
Come on!
出てくれ！
ああっ 出た！
It came!
It's raining, but... Oh, well.
（佐藤）
雨の中だけど… ま いいか
（圭）
頭を狙ってる？
It's aiming for the head?
Hey! You try for the head too!
（圭）
おい！　お前も頭を狙ってみろ！
God, why... do I have to...
listen to this?
（圭ＩＢＭ）
ったく なんで皮肉… を
言われなきゃ…
はぁ？
Oh, look at that.
おお すごいな
命令無視もするのか
It even ignores orders.
（圭ＩＢＭ）
１人で可哀想だ… から…
構ってやってた…
I was only hanging out with him
'cause he was always alone.
（圭）
そんな昔のこと 言わないでくれよ
That was so long ago.
I wish it wouldn't bring that up now.
Nagai.
（野村）
永井… 君
いい… 逃げ… ろ
It's okay. Just run.
No way.
嫌だ
Why are you... doing this?
（野村）
なんで… 俺を…
Because I never cared about anyone.
僕は誰とも関わってこなかったし
そんな必要なかったし―
I didn't see the need.
I didn't care about others.
他人なんて どうでもよかった
But I want to save you.
でも あんたは助けたい
That's why...
だから…
...I'm going to drop you from here.
It's the only way.
ここから落とす　それしかない
There. If you land on the bushes,
あそこだ　植え込みに落ちれば
生存率は確実に上がる
you'll have a much higher chance
of surviving.
Kei Nagai has come into view!
（モニター音声:キャスター）
見えました　永井圭です
He appears to be trying to drop a
researcher off the roof.
研究員らしき人物を
落とそうとしているように見えます
Is that a hostage?
人質ということでしょうか？
（太居(ふとい)）
どうするつもりだ？
このままでは逃げられるぞ
What are you planning to do?
At this rate, he'll get away.
Mr. Tosaki.
戸崎さん…
くっ…
-Colonel Kouma.
-What is it?
コウマ陸佐
（コウマ）
何だ？
The unit... How quickly can you bring
the Anti-Ajin Special Forces here?
対亜… “対亜人特選群”は
何分で呼べますか？
ふざけるな！
Don't be absurd! The anti-Ajins
were a temporary provisional unit
“対亜”は別種対策が
悪化した時のため―
急きょ発足させられた
仮の部隊にすぎん！
formed when our response
to a variant failed!
コウマ陸佐 聞いてください
Colonel Kouma, listen to me.
I have no intention
of making my forces fight
（コウマ）
別種への対抗策も
見つけられていない現状で―
部下を戦闘させる気…
when we still don't know how to--
今日がチャンスなんです！
-Today is our chance!
-What do you mean?
どういう意味だ？
Why exactly didn't Hat use his IBM today?
Shouldn't that be the real question?
なぜ 今日 帽子は
ＩＢＭを使わなかったのか
こう考えるべきじゃありませんか？
It's because he couldn't use it today.
今日は使うことができなかった
I don't know the reason,
but it's extremely likely.
理由は分かりませんが
その可能性は高い
There's something different about today
than when he stole Tanaka.
田中奪還時と今日では
何かが違うんです
んん…
こんなチャンスは
二度とないかもしれません
We may not have another chance like this.
Colonel Kouma...
コウマ陸佐！
Bend your knees!
（圭）
ひざを“く”の字にして！
いきますよ！
Are you ready?
（野村）
うっ… ま… 待て
Wait.
Can you see that?
あれが見えるか？
“あれ”？
That?
あっ…
Now then, how are you going
to fight like that?
（佐藤ＩＢＭ）
さあ それで どう戦う？
You try for the head too.
（圭ＩＢＭ）
お前も… 頭を…
（佐藤）
ん！？
ああっ！
Was that... Mr. Sato's?
（圭）
今の… 佐藤さんの？
Part of Kei Nagai's memory played back
in my mind?
（佐藤）
永井君の記憶の一部が
流れ込んできた？
So this is what happens
when they butt heads.
頭同士だと
こんなことが起こるのか
Nagai... go.
永井… 君… 行け
（キャスターの悲鳴）
-Did he drop him?
-He just dropped him!
（記者）
落としたのか？
落としたぞ！
Okay, fine then.
（コウマ）
分かった いいだろう
だが その仮説が正しかったらだ
But only if your hypothesis is right.
You heard him.
What do you think, Dr. Ogura?!
聞いていただろ？
どうなんだ？　オグラ博士
IBM's aren't as all-powerful as you think.
ＩＢＭは 君たちが思ってるほど
万能じゃない
They have various weak points.
つけいる隙は幾つもあって…
ん？
Can you see that, Nagai?
（野村）
あれが見えるか？　永井君
That river is for drainage.
あの川は放水路だ
大雨の時は海まで水門が開く
When it's raining hard,
the sluice gates open to the sea.
It's risky, but you may be able to escape.
賭けだが
あれなら逃げられるかも知れない
（圭）
はぁっ… はぁっ… はぁっ…
Doctor, please avoid revealing
any information about Ajins.
（ＳＰ）
博士　亜人について 情報を
漏らすようなことは避けてくれ
あ… ああ そうだったなぁ
Oh, that's right.
In that case, no comment.
ということで ノーコメントだ
I see.
そうですか…
（佐藤）
ふん！
あっ…
うっ… ぐわっ…
うわあー！
（水の音）
（モニター音声:キャスター）
あ！　永井圭が川へ！
Nagai dove into the river!
God damn it.
（太居）
何ということだ…
Let's go. The sample got away.
帰ろう　サンプルは逃げた
くっ…
Kei Nagai has just jumped
from the facility roof into the river!
（テレビ音声:キャスター）
永井圭が施設の屋上から
川へ飛び込みました
After dropping someone
who looked like a researcher,
研究員らしき人物を落とした後
自らも川へ飛び降りました
he threw himself into the river.
The river is swollen and muddied.
川の水かさは ここ数日の雨で
大きく増しており…
Big brother.
お兄ちゃん…
（テレビ音声）
濁流となっています
TO BE CONTINUED
If my wish would come true
願い叶(かな)うなら
もう一度
Once again
I wanna touch your heart
君の心に
触れていたい
No matter how dark it gets
どんな闇でも
探してるんだ
I'll be searching
For my one
たったひとつの
光を
And only light
As I look up to the stars
Even though you are far
遠いけど
You're looking up at the same starry sky
同じ星空　見上げてる
In the sky of my heart
心の空には
雫(こぼ)れ落ちそうな
It's about to spill over
Your smile and
君の笑顔と
ぬくもり
Your warmth
Hear me
Until I went away and
Faced the lonely days
愛することの意味なんて
I thought I could understand
What it means to love
分かってたつもりだった
Feeling everything that
Was right in front of me
大切なもの失って
Losing something precious
本当の愛に気付いて
Realizing real love
I'll tell you now
I'll tell you now,
Just how close you are